Finding Aid for Lawyers' Wives of Washtenaw County Records, 1955-1980
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Lawyers' Wives of Washtenaw County records 1955-1980
Lawyers' Wives of Washtenaw County
0.3 linear ft. and 2 oversize volumes
043 Bk 2
Social organization of wives and widows of Washtenaw County lawyers. Records document history, membership, activities, and administration of the organization from 1955 to 1980.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The record group was donated by Mrs. William Pierce (Donor no. 8966 ) in May 2000.
The record group is open to research.
Lawyers' Wives of Washtenaw County was previously Women's Auxiliary of the Washtenaw County Bar Association (1955-1964). It changed its name to Lawyers' Wives of Washtenaw County in 1965 and became an Auxiliary of Lawyers' Wives of Michigan. The organization's purpose is to promote the interests of the Lawyers' Wives of Washtenaw County and to encourage sociability among the members of the Auxiliary. The membership of the organization consists of the wives and widows of Washtenaw County lawyers.
The Lawyers' Wives of Washtenaw County records includes information regarding the activities, administration and membership of the organization from 1955 to 1980. It also includes some reports and meeting minutes from its parent organization, Lawyers' Wives of Michigan, especially materials related to its involvement in Law Day activities from 1974 to 1978. The record group is divided into two series: Organization History and Administrative Records and Lawyers' Wives of Michigan.
Subjects:
Lawyers' Wives of Washtenaw County.; Lawyers' spouses--Michigan.; Lawyers' spouses--Michigan--Washtenaw County.; Lawyers' Wives of Michigan.; Women--Michigan--Washtenaw County--Societies and clubs.
Subjects - Visual Materials:
Lawyers' Wives of Washtenaw County.
Genre Terms:
Photographs.
- Organization History and Administrative Records
  The first series, Organization History and Administrative Records, contains two scrapbooks regarding the history of the organization from 1955 to 1976, including programs and membership directories, president's reports, budgets, newspaper clippings, photographs, brochures, invitation cards, and newsletters. This series also contains meeting agendas and minutes, budgets, newsletters from 1976 to 1980, a copy of the 1971 constitution and by-laws, and some photos, slides and negatives of the organization's activities.
  - Scrapbooks "Lawyers' Wives of Washtenaw County Through the Years" 1955-1976, 2 volumes (Volume 1)
  - Board Meeting Agenda and Minutes, 1977-1978 (Box 1)
  - Budgets, 1977-1979 (Box 1)
  - Newsletter Pro Feminis Loquitur (This speaks for the women), 1977-1980 (Box 1)
  - Constitution and By-laws, 1971 (Box 1)
  - Historian's File, 1966-1973 (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 1969-1974 (Box 1)
- Lawyers' Wives of Michigan
  The second series, Lawyers' Wives of Michigan, consists of records related to the parent organization: Lawyers' Wives of Michigan. It mainly contains meeting minutes, reports, newsletters and materials related to annual Law Day programs covering 1974 to 1978, including reports, memos, notes and planning guides.
  - Law Day, 1974-1978 (Box 1)
  - Newsletter, 1976-1978 (Box 1)
  - Executive Board and Council Meeting, 1976-1977 (Box 1)
  - Lawyers' Wives of Calhoun County Reports, ca. 1976 (Box 1)